{
    "id": "7c67a3e0dbec4075adac98ff234285bc",
    "title": "Parts Of Speech Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I was not expecting this from you. Identify the preposition.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "not",
                "this",
                "from"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She could not believe her eyes when she saw him there. Identify the verb.",
            "description": "A verb is an action word.",
            "answers": [
                "not",
                "saw",
                "when"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The girl sat beside her mother and kept talking. Identify the preposition",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "sat",
                "beside",
                "and"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He was so angry that he shouted at the top of his voice. Identify the noun",
            "description": "A noun is the name of a person, place, thing, quality or concept. ",
            "answers": [
                "he",
                "angry",
                "voice"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "It took me quite some time to get used to living in the city. Identify the adverb",
            "description": "An adverb is a word that modifies a verb, adjective or another adverb. ",
            "answers": [
                "quite",
                "used to",
                "living"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She was angry but she said nothing. Identify the adjective.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "angry",
                "but",
                "nothing"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The teacher congratulated the students on their marvellous performance. Identify the adjective",
            "description": "An adjective is a word that modifies a noun. ",
            "answers": [
                "congratulated",
                "marvellous",
                "performance"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She does not seem to understand the importance of keeping information confidential. Identify the adjective",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "seem",
                "keeping",
                "confidential"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Although buying is better than renting, few people can actually afford to buy a home these days. Identify the conjunction.",
            "description": "A conjunction is a word used to connect two clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "Although",
                "better",
                "actually"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "It cannot get better than this. Identify the verb",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "get",
                "better",
                "than"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He injured his ankle while playing football yesterday. Identify the adverb",
            "description": "Time words are adverbs.",
            "answers": [
                "injured",
                "while",
                "yesterday"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "That child does not eat anything but hamburgers. Identify the adjective.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "not",
                "but"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}